A Guide to the Archives Vertical File Collection, 1985-2011
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Archives Vertical File Collection, 1985-2011
The Library of Virginia
39030
1.35 cubic feet (3 boxes) and 2 oversize folders
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Received from various donors at various times.
Scope and Content
The Archives Vertical File collection contains a variety of research material including newspaper clippings, genealogies, obituaries, copies of publications, research notes, and biographies. In general, the types of items one might find are loose papers, pedigree charts, newspaper clippings, and items that are not suitable for shelving. The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Also contained in the files are family histories which may not have been widely published. Incomplete genealogies are included for the following families: Campbell, Davis, Draper, Griffin, Guthrie, Hamilton, Harbin, Harwood, Hatcher, Henderson, Johnstone, Klein, Petty, Reeves, Reneau, Van Buren, and Vaughan.
Contents List
- Archives Vertical File Collection, 1985-2011., Extent: 3 boxes and 2 oversize folders. (Box 1-3 and Oversize Box 104)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Two folders of oversize items in Oversize Box 104.
  - Account book page, undated (Box 1)
  - [___?] Beach, history of structures built 1883-1897 (Box 1)
  - Bondurant, Jean Pierre. Abjuration, 3 Oct. 1697 (Box 1)
  - Bontecou, Eleanor (Box 1)
  - Byrd Mill (Louisa County, Va.) (Box 1)
  - Byrd Presbyterian Church (Goochland, Va.) recollections, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Campbell family (Box 1)
  - County Court and Overseers of the Poor Rate [locality unspecified, date ca. 19th century] (Box 1)
  - Currency conversion chart, undated [pre-1776] (Box 104)
  - Davis, Agnes, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Davis family (Box 1)
  - Dismal Swamp conservation efforts (Box 1)
  - Draper family (Box 1)
  - Envelope, 17 August 1858, William Drinkard to Chas. B. Shaw, Esq. (Box 1)
  - Ferries (Bedford County, Va.) (Box 1)
  - Freedom Before Emancipation, Mid-Ocean News, 10 August 2007 (Box 1)
  - French and English newspaper collection, 1932, 1936, 1940 (Box 104)
    Includes issues of Le Rire (1 October 1932); L'Illustre du Petit Journal (6 and 27 September, 9 August, and 15 November 1936); Marianne (28 February 1940); The War (27 September 1940); and an undated page ripped from an unidentified periodical published by The Sun Engraving Co., Ltd. Also included is a typed reminiscence (2 leaves) of the donor's life in Egypt, where he was born in 1937. Events discussed date into the late 1960's. The donor chose to remain anonymous.
  - Griffin family (Box 1)
  - Guthrie family (Box 1)
  - Halifax County (Va.) - transcripts and photocopies of miscellaneous 18th century court documents (Box 1)
  - Hamilton family (Box 1)
  - Harbin family (Box 1)
  - Harwood family (Box 1)
  - Hatcher family (Box 1)
  - Henderson family (Box 1)
  - Hillman's Tollgate (Winchester, Va.) (Box 1)
  - Historical Event Unveiled: True History Becomes Alive by Herman B. Turner (Box 1)
  - Holbrook family gravesite, Franklin County, Ga., photographs (Box 1)
    One of the markers is for Revolutionary War soldier Jesse Holbrook, Virginia Militia, Goochland County.
  - Johnstone family (Box 1)
  - Kello, Samuel. Letter fragment (Box 1)
  - Kisling, Simmerman, Hudson, Piper houses (Wythe County, Va.) (Box 1)
  - Klein family (Box 1)
  - Lawson family (Box 1)
  - Lease information (ca. 19th century) (Box 1)
  - Medyan, Parviz M. Letter to Tom Daschle, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Marriage bonds and ministers' returns, Roanoke County, Va., 1838-1852, abstracts (Box 1)
  - Merrimac, clippings re: (Box 1)
  - Montgomery, John (Box 1)
  - Muster roll, Hospital Dept., Winchester, Va., March-April 1862, transcription by Sammy Copenhaver (Box 1)
  - Obituaries (Box 2)
  - Oliver, Leslie Radin. Recipes from Times Past (Box 2)
  - Pankerson-Cherry-Beveridge families (Box 2)
  - Petition [?], 1774 [?] (Box 2)
  - Petty family (Box 2)
  - Proceedings, unnamed court case, ca. 18th/19th century (Box 2)
  - Randolph family (Box 2)
  - Reeves family (Box 2)
  - Remembering Pap Ben: Bennie Bryan Coffey, 1917-2008 (Box 2)
  - Reneau family (Box 2)
  - Reynolds Metals Company: The Landscape [photocopied brochure] (Box 2)
  - Rhode Island - Voided 1888 U.S. Congress act re: purchase of land in RI (Box 104)
  - Rogers, Bill. Pamphlets, 2003 (Box 2)
  - St. Mary's Academy [locality unknown] (Box 2)
  - Saura (Saraw, Cheraw) Indians and two Virginia Indian legends (Box 2)
  - Sandy Springs (Md.) (Box 2)
  - Spanish Jesuit martyrs of Virginia, various illustrations (Box 2)
  - State papers (calendar of), 1710-1715 (Box 2)
  - Supreme Court [Va.? U.S.?} (Box 2)
  - Tracy family (Box 2)
  - Transcript excerpts, Edmund Randolph's History of Virginia (Box 2)
  - Turner, Edith, of Southampton (American Beacon article, 24 March 1820) (Box 2)
  - Unidentified portrait (copy; original in Corcoran Art Gallery) (Box 2)
  - Van Buren family (Box 2)
  - Vaughan family (Box 2)
  - Washington-Henry Academy (Atlee, Va.) (Box 3)
  - Watts, Van (Box 3)
  - Williamsburg (Va.) and Yorktown (Va.) extracts (deed, will, order books, etc., 16th, 17th, 18th centuries) (Box 3)
  - [___?] Wormeley captivity and confinement, 1778 [?] (Box 3)
  - The Wythe Grays: Harpers Ferry and Beyond, article from the Wythe County Historical Review, Number 72, Winter 2008-2009 (Box 3)